Guide to the Elizabeth Burtner papers, 1903-2003 MS2150
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Dance program at The George Washington University, 1938-1995; MS2150 Series 1; 3 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 2)
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Salem Witchcraft, 04/24/1959-04/25/1959 (Box 1, Folder 129)
    "the Accused"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Salem Witchcraft, 04/24/1959-04/25/1959 (Box 1, Folder 130)
    "People of the community and the Accused"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Salem Witchcraft, 04/24/1959-04/25/1959 (Box 1, Folder 131)
    "from SALEM WITCHCRAFT Gossipmonger and two young girls 4/24,25/'59 (premiere performance 4/12/45)"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--The Troubadour, 04/24/1959-04/25/1959 (Box 1, Folder 132)
    "From: THE TROUBADOR Arthur Bauman 4/24,25/59"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 133)
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--The Wife of Usher's Well, 03/17/1961-03/18/1961 (Box 1, Folder 134)
    "From: THE WIFE OF USHER'S WELL Lavinia and three sons 3/17 and 18/61"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--The Wife of Usher's Well, 03/17/1961-03/18/1961 (Box 1, Folder 135)
    "From: THE WIFE OF USHER'S WELL Elsphath, the daughter, Ann Roland 3/17 and 18/61"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--The Wife of Usher's Well, 03/17/1961-03/18/1961 (Box 1, Folder 136)
    "From: THE WIFE OF USHER'S WELL Spirit of the Three Dead Sons - Evelyn Arana, Nancy Haines, Jo Ann Mason 3/17,18/61"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Shapes in Space, 03/02/1962-03/02/1962 (Box 1, Folder 137)
    "From: SHAPES IN SPACE Ann Roland and Heddy Lowrie (standing) 3/2,3/62"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Shapes in Space, 03/02/1962-03/03/1962 (Box 1, Folder 138)
    "From: SHAPES IN SPACE Heddy Lowrie and Ann Roland 3/2 and3/'62"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--La Marionette, 03/29/1963-03/30/1963 (Box 1, Folder 139)
    "From: LA MARIONETTE Ann Roland 3/29,30/63"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--La Marionette, 03/29/1963-03/30/1963 (Box 1, Folder 140)
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Nocturne, 03/29/1963-03/30/1963 (Box 1, Folder 141)
    "From: NOCTURNE Arthur Bauman and Company Sarah Ford, Marcia Lerner, Eugania Schoettler 3/29,30/63"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Nocturne, 03/29/1963-03/30/1963 (Box 1, Folder 142)
    "From: NOCTURNE Arthur Bauman Co., (guest artists) 3/29,30/63"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--A Day in the Life, 03/29/1963-03/30/1963 (Box 1, Folder 143)
    Text on photograph: "A DAY IN THE LIFE Ron Scheraga with umbrella Leslie Levitt on the left of Scheraga"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--A Day in the Life, 03/29/1963-03/30/1963 (Box 1, Folder 144)
    Text on photograph: "A DAY IN THE LIFE Ron Scheraga 3rd from the left; Leslie Levitt 4th from the left; Larry Adair extreme right sitting on stool"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--A Day in the Life, 04/17/1964-04/18/1964 (Box 1, Folder 145)
    Text on photograph: "A DAY IN THE LIFE Larry Adair on left; Richard Mitchell, center; Ron Scheraga right, crouching"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Jeremiah, 04/17/1963-04/18/1964 (Box 1, Folder 146)
    "From: JEREMIAH - Lamentation - Religion in Life Program 4/17,18/64"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Unidentified photograph, 1960 ca. --1962 ca. (Box 1, Folder 147)
    Text on photograph: "Ann Roland in the air - stage right- art major 1960's"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert, 1965-1972 (Box 1, Folder 148)
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Carnival - Carousel, 04/07/1965-04/08/1965 (Box 1, Folder 149)
    "From: CARNIVAL - CAROUSEL 4/7,8/1965"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Partita V, 03/25/1966-03/26/1966 (Box 1, Folder 150)
    "From: PARTITA V Leonard Hanitchak and ensemble 3/25,26/66 choreography by Doris Humphrey premiered 1942"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Scenes from Currier and Ives, 03/25/1966-03/26/1966 (Box 1, Folder 151)
    Text on photograph: "Scenes from Currier and Ives Scene II Leslie Levitt and Leonard Hanitchak Property of Dance Production Groups George Washington University Bldg J Please return"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Linda Braudste, 1965 ca. --1970 ca. (Box 1, Folder 152)
    Text on photograph: "Linda Braudste, Dance major - late 60's (younger sister of Peggy Cooper Cofritz)
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Jeannie Jones, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 153)
    Text on photograph: "Jeannie Jones 1966's C [sic]"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Leslie Levitt, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 154)
    Text on photograph: "Leslie Levitt 1966's C [sic] first in line, stage right"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Leslie Levitt, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 155)
    Text on photograph: "Leslie Levitt 1966's [sic]"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Witchcraft, 04/14/1967-04/15/1967 (Box 1, Folder 156)
    "From: Witchcraft Jeanne Jones (one of the two young girls)"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Witchcraft, 04/14/1967-04/15/1967 (Box 1, Folder 157)
    Text on photograph: "From: Witchcraft 4/14,15/67 Two young girls Jeanne Jones and Lesley Vosen"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Witchcraft, 04/14/1967-04/15/1967 (Box 1, Folder 158)
    Text on photograph: "From: Witchcraft Carol Surman, the Accused Premiered 1946 4/14,15/67"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Witchcraft, 04/14/1967-04/15/1967 (Box 1, Folder 159)
    Text on photograph: "From: Witchcraft Carol Surman, the Accused 4/14,15/67"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Protest, 04/14/1967-04/15/1967 (Box 1, Folder 160)
    Text on photograph: "PROTEST Silent Protest (one of three) Clare Crandall, Carol Surman, Nancy Tartt (Confrontation Protest, first; COnstant Protest, second) 4/14,15/67 (see program) (listing of dancers in order??)"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Protest, 04/14/1967-04/15/1967 (Box 1, Folder 161)
    Text on photograph: "From: PROTEST (see program) 4/14,15/67"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Protest, 04/14/1967-04/15/1967 (Box 1, Folder 162)
    Text on photograph: "From PROTEST Silent Protest (see program) 4/14,15/67"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Protest, 04/14/1967-04/15/1967 (Box 1, Folder 163)
    Text on photograph: "From: PROTEST Silent Protest (see program) 4/14,15/67"
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert--Protest, 04/14/1967-04/15/1967 (Box 1, Folder 164)
  - Artists in residence, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 165)
  - Artists in residence, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 166)
  - Artists in residence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 167)
  - Artists in residence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 168)
  - Artists in residence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 169)
    "Al Huang and Suzanne Pierce"
  - Artists in residence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 170)
    Text on photograph: "Al Huang and Suzanne Pierce"
  - Artists in residence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 171)
  - Artists in residence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 172)
    "David Gordon, Steve Paxton, Yvonne Rainer perform the "Stairs" segment of Yvonne Rainer's "The Mind Is a Muscle," 1966
  - Artists in residence, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 173)
  - Artists in residence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 174)
    Text on photograph: "Rudy Perez Dancer, Choreographer, Teacher of the Rudy Perez Theatre"
  - Artists in residence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 175)
    Text on photograph: "Al Huang (Al Chung-Liang Huang)
  - Artists in residence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 176)
  - Artists in residence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 177)
  - Carnival, 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Carnival, 07/30/1952 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Text on photograph: "AMERICANA CARNIVALE -- Students and faculty made merry in the Yard on July 30, 1952, when carnival characters came to the University for the evening. Left to right, Harry Hughes; Nancy Dilli; Mr. Merry-go-round Man, Prof. Donald Kline; Master Barker, Prof. John F. Latimer; Mr. Balloon Man, Prof. Burnice H. Jarman; Nell Weaver; George Washington, Graham King; and Frank Haynes."
  - Carnival, 07/28/1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    "Midway: School of Government Clown, Allurd, Mumford 7/28/52"
  - Carnival, 07/28/1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Text on photograph: "Phyllis Allen (1)" "Performance: Carousel Don Kline, Merry Go Round Man 7/28/52"
  - Carnival, 07/28/1952 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    "Festival Performance: CAROUSEL continued Tom Pence and Milica Hasalova 7/28/52"
  - Carnival, 07/28/1952 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    "Festival Performance: CAROUSEL by Dance Production Groups Tom Pence and Milica Hasalova; Don Kline, Merry Go Round Man 4/28/52"
  - Carnival, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    "Festival Performance: continued Carnival 1952"
  - Carnival, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    "Festival Performace: continued 1952"
  - Carnival, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    "Concession Booth: Dale Kline, Dr. Latimer (in high silk hat)"
  - Carnival, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    "Concession Booth: Dale Kline and Dr. Latimer Carnival 1952"
  - Carnival, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Text on photograph: "John Kline, son of Donald C. Kline, Prof. of Art. Lyn Henderson, daughter of Leon Henderson, Activities Chairman of the Student Council. Peter Kniskoru, of Tunisia. Joan Drew, daughter of Gerald A. Drew, Dir. Gen. of Foreign Service - director of Jr. Coll. division of Folk Festival. The Frontier wagon - Summer Schoool Folk Festival - 1953"
  - Carnival, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    "Midway: Smoky Mountain Cabin, the Tall Tales Booth being finished - Columbia College, 1953"
  - Carnival, 07/22/1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Text on photograph: "Dale Kline, daughter of Prof. Donald C. Kline, Prof. of Art. Hal Robinson, director of Law School group. Dr. Vera Mowny, Ass't Prof. of English at the Univ., Technical Director of Arena Stage. Christopher Mowny. Ellen Sincoff, Publicity Chairman of the Student Council. Outside the Southern Appalachain Smoky Mountain Cabin where Tall Tales were told -- Folk Festival -- 1953 Summer School."
  - Carnival, 07/22/1953 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    "The Midway: Smoky Mountain Cabin, Tall Tales -- Columbia College Professor Poe Leggette, Teller of Tall Tales is Head of Speech/Drama Department. Dale Kline is daughter of Donald C. Kline, Art Dept."
  - Carnival, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Text on photograph: "Graham King, Jr. Coll. -- Mary Pope, Lil of the Can Can Gals, formerly of the Met. Opera Corps de Ballet -- outside the Bum Steer dance hall - Summer School Folk Festival 1953"
  - Carnival, 07/22/1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    "The Midway: Phyllis Allen, Dance Hall Girl 7/22/53"
  - Carnival, 07/28/1954 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    "Fiesta Performance: Zuni Corn Dance - Koshare (Delight Maker) Don Johnson and tribesmen - Junior College 7/28/1954"
  - Carnival, 07/28/1954 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    "Fiesta Performance: Zuni Corn Dance continued Southwest Fiesta 7/28/54"
  - Carnival, 07/28/1954 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    "Fiesta Performance: COWBOY JAMBOREE Cowgirls - Gayla April, Loydell Jones, Milica Hasalova, Kitty Lee Landess - Southwest Fiesta 7/28/54"
  - Carnival, 07/28/1954 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    "Fiesta Performance: COWBOY JAMBOREE, Western Square Southwest Fiesta 7/28/54"
  - Carnival, 07/28/1954 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    "Fiesta Performance: COWBOY JAMBOREE Southwest Fiesta 7/28/54"
  - Carnival, 07/28/1954 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    "Fiesta Performance: BORDERTOWN School of Government - The Dirty Shame Saloon - Siesta Sal, Lillemor Spitzer; Cowboys, George Mozer and Dayton Coe; Pianist, Ken Flieger - Southwest Fiesta 7/28/54"
  - Carnival, 07/28/1954 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    "Midway: Chuck Wagon Southwest Fiesta 7/28/54"
  - Carnival, 07/28/1954 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    "Midway: Drum-making Booth Southwest Fiesta 7/28/54"
  - Carnival, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    "Don Kline and Julia Kline, son, Jon, daughter, Dale"
  - Carnival, 07/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    "The Big Top Performance 7/27/55"
  - Carnival, 07/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Carnival, 07/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Carnival, 07/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    "All for a Ride? Beverly Borden and Chick Trueblood"
  - Carnival, 07/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Carnival, 07/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Carnival, 07/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    "Big Top Performance: The Lady Lion Tamer - Verlyn Brown 7/27/55"
  - Carnival, 07/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    "The Big Top Performance: Animal Act - Tigers"
  - Carnival, 07/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    "The Big Top Performance: The Grand Parade - Caged Panthers and Keepers - Jane Parris, Gayla April, with Howard Davis and Steve Gerachis 7/27/55"
  - Carnival, 07/27/1955 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Carnival, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    "Cruise Performance: EMBARKTION [sic] G G Cain (formerly G G Horsburg) 1956"
  - Carnival, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    "Cruise Performance: CUBA - Cafe Tropicana, Havana Tourist, G G Cain 1956"
  - Carnival, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Carnival, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Carnival, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Text on photograph: "G G Cain (previously Horsburgh) 1956 Carnival"
  - Carnival, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Carnival, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Carnival, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    "From: Carribean [sic] Holiday 1956 Summer School Carnival DP Groups"
  - Carnival, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Carnival, 1957-1960 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Carnival, 07/24/1957 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    Text on photograph: "ACE HIGH Two gamblers - Dick Bushey and Jim Black - From: Showboat Performance 7/24/57" "Richard Busby Jerry Osborne - in the air - from ACE HIGH"
  - Carnival, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    "Broadway Performance: Stage Setting - art work by Professor Don Kline, Art Department Manhattan Merry-Go-Round 1958"
  - Carnival, 07/22/1958 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    "Hawaiian Review: Jane Firey and Dick Bushey Carnival 7/22/59"
  - Carnival, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    "Hawaiian Review: Kay Buchanan, Patty Snead - Dancer with Bamboo Sticks, and Dick Bushey -- The Fleet's In 1959"
  - Carnival, 07/28/1960 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    "Midway: Status Seeker - School of Government Carnival U.S.A. 1960 7/28/60"
  - Correspondence, 1940-1978 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Dance Production Groups and Orchesis, 1937-1968 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Dance Production Groups, 1961-1969 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Dance Production Groups--Articles, 1943-1964 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - "The Drama of Dance" As a Universal Language, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - "The Drama of Dance" As a Universal Language, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    Text on photograph: "From: Alluripu (Invocation) by Bhamumathi and Bhaskar from South India"
  - "The Drama of Dance" As a Universal Language, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    Text on photograph: "Wasisto Soerjadiningrat and Ksentjoro Koentjaraningrat, Asia dance and fighing dance"
  - "The Drama of Dance" As a Universal Language, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    "South, South East Asia: Fighting Dance"
  - "The Drama of Dance" As a Universal Language, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    Text on photograph: "Mr. Benedictus Suharto (as Tjakil) and Mrs. Suharto (as Arjuna) portraying a fight in the Solonese style of Javanese dance-drama from Indonesia."
  - Faculty Follies, 12/17/1948 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Folk Dance, 1947-1962 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Folk Dance Special Performanes, 1958-1969 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Lectures, Dance Demonstrations, 1949-1969 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Lectures, Dance Demonstrations--Mother and Two Eligible Daughters, 02/23/1951 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    Text on photograph: "From: Mother and Two Eligible Daughters - from left to right: Sarah Horsburgh, Tom Pence, Patricia Weaver, and Betty Silverman Feb. 1951"
  - Lectures, Dance Demonstrations--Military Ball, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    Text on photograph: "From Military Ball - Patricia Gernova and Tom Pence (Patricia sometimes listed as Lola) permiered 1953 DPG Dance Concert"
  - Master Classes, Symposia, Workshops, Studio Nights, Radio, Films, 1937-1972 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - May Day Presentations, 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Plays, Musicals, Homecoming shows, 1944-1968 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Plays, Musicals, Homecoming shows--Ladies in Hades, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Plays, Musicals, Homecoming shows--Homecoming, 09/04/1954 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    Text on photograph: "1954 Homecoming PEP RALLY and VARIETY SHOW 9/4/54 -Lillemor Spitzer, The Girl - Tom Pence (center), downstage - George Mozer to rear of Pence - Title: Who is the Girl?"
  - Plays, Musicals, Homecoming shows--Homecoming, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    Text on photograph: "From: 1954 Homecoming Pep Rally and Variety Show - George Mozer, Lillemor Spitzer, Tom Pence - Dance Production Groups - Title: Who is the Girl?"
  - Plays, Musicals, Homecoming shows--Brigadoon, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    Text on photograph: "BRIGADOON: Peter Pazzolini, DPGs Homecoming"
  - Presentations, Recitals, Concerts in Modern Dance, 1937-1970 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Social Dance, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    Text on photograph: "The George Washington University Summer 1952 - A beachcomber theme brought students in bare feet to the Wednesday night dance on Lisner Terrace of the University. Social and square dances of varying themes are held each Wednesday for students and faculty members of the University." "A night of social dance on terrace of G street Lisner Library during 1952 summer dance program. From audience downstage left: Steve Luke; centerstage, Dean Virginia Kirkbride with Tom Pence; stage right, Milica Hasalova and John Williams."
  - Social Dance, 10/31/1952 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    Text on photograph: POST Staff pix by John Daly. UNIDENTIFIED dancers cover the floor at G.W. Friday night." "Social dance, Student Union on G St. Oct. 31st, 1952 (a carry-over of the new summer dance program)"
  - Student activities--GWU Manual of Policies and Procedures, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Students--1940s, 1939-1989 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Students--late 1940s - early 1950s, 1949-1967 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Students, 1950 ca. (Box 2, Folder 79)
    Text on photograph: "Louise Whiting GWU Dance Production Groups (DPG.) 1946-1951"
  - Students, 1950 ca. (Box 2, Folder 80)
    Text on photograph: "Tom Pence DPG's 1947-54 G.W. Univ. - Louise Whiting DPG's 1946-1951 G.W. Univ."
  - Students, 1950 ca. (Box 2, Folder 81)
    Text on photograph: "Louise Whiting - Tom Pence DPG Concert GW Univ."
  - Students--late 1940s - early 1950s, 1956-2002 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Students, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    Text on photograph: "G.W.U. Dance Production Group, 1953 - Tom Pence, Milica Hasalova, Claudia Chapline, right (in rehearsal)"
  - Students--late 1950s, 1958-1976 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Students, 04/25/1958-04/26/1958 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    Text on photograph: "Greensleeves (choreographed by Gregg Mayer) - Gregg Mayer and Arthur Bauman - Dance Concert April 25 and 26, 1958 DPG GWU"
  - Students--1960s, 1966-1996 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Students--1970s, 1976-1994 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Students--1980s, 1983-1995 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Annual Spring Dance Concert, undated (Flat box 8, Folder 2)
    Watercolor sketch of costume, signed Don Kline. Text on reverse: "Donald C. Kline, Head of Art Dept., GWU; Artisitc Advisor for DPG in Cosuming, Lighting, Stage Decore; Designed many costumes for DPGroups."
  - Students, 1947 ca. --1954 ca. (Flat box 8, Folder 3)
    Text on photograph: "Tom Pence. Dance Production Groups, GWUniv. 1947-1954 (1952-1953 - alumnus; 1954 assistant to director of DPG's - Burtner) Major in School of Government (following graduation - U.S. Gov. Foreign Service)
  - Dance Award, 1980 (Flat box 8, Folder 4)
    award reads "Metropolitan Dance Association gratefully presents this 1980 Dance Awards to Elizabeth Burtner for continued commitment and outstanding contribution to dance in the Washington area."
- Dancers and trends in dance, 1903-2003; MS2150 Series 2; 7 Linear feet (Box 4, Box 5, Box 6, Box 7, Box 3)
  This series contains clippings, subject files about dance notation, specific performers, choreographers, and dance companies, and theatrical and souvenir programs. Burtner compiled chronological files of newspaper and magazine clippings about dancers, trends in dance, and dance performances. Additional clippings, as well as brochures, biographies, photographs, promotional materials, and correspondence are included in the dancer subject files. The Laban Art of Movement Guild magazine and other newsletters and publications are included in the dance notation subject files.
  - Bennington School of the Dance, 1938-1984; 1938-1946; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Clippings, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Clippings, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Clippings, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Clippings, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1982-1985 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Clippings, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Dance notation, 1948-1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dance notation, 1967-1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Dance notation--Laban Art of Movement Guild, 1950-1957 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dance notation--Laban Art of Movement Guild, 1958-1960 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Dance notation--Laban Centre, 1960-1995 ca. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Dancers--Ailey, Alvin, 1968-2001 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Dancers--Balanchine, 1949-1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dancers--Balasarawati and daughter Lakshmi and the American Society for Eastern Arts, 1962-1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Dancers--Baryshnikov, Mikhail, 1989-2001 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Dancers--Bettis, Valerie, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Dancers--Bird, Bonnie, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Dancers--Cohen, Selma Jeanne, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Dancers--Cunningham, Merce, 1959-2002 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Dancers--Cunningham, Merce and dance company lecture demonstration, March 15 (no year provided); Series 2 (Flat box 8, Folder 8)
  - Dancers--Collins, Janet, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Dancers--Davis, Evelyn, 1936-2000 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Dancers--Duncan, Isadora, 1903-1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Dancers--Dunham, Katherine, 1955-1971 (Box 5, Folder 17)